<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>blog to self-introduce, rat race, get a skin-in-the-game in wording, etc.</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on blog to self-introduce, rat race, get a skin-in-the-game in wording, etc.</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>sound event detection: what and how</title>
      <link>/posts/sed1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/sed1/</guid>
      <description>Sound event detection: what and how Layout:
 Problem definition Deep learning Methods Challenges A real example References  Problem definition Sound event detection (SED): Task to identify the type of sound event. May also identify start/end time in the long audio stream.
Like most problems, SED relies on labeling, or the start/end time locations. A concept called weak labeling exists in SED world, which refers to labels telling only types of sound events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>creative coding: how&#39;s it made?</title>
      <link>/posts/cc1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cc1/</guid>
      <description>Creative coding: 1st attempt layout:
 creative coding and javascript generative learning  Creative coding and js Generative learning So can I do this?
Looking into my toolbox, the only thing that somewhat links to art and creativity is deep learning.
Question: What can deep learning do in creative coding/art?
This is obviously not a new question at all. We have all those generative models like conditional gans that turn pictures into art works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>stock: rdfn vs z</title>
      <link>/posts/stock1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/stock1/</guid>
      <description>A summary of a Zillow and Redfin comparison SA article by Dan Owens. Both positive quarterly earnings in the third quarter 2020. Not profitable yearly though.
Housing demand surge by COVID can be a reason.
How to be profitable remains questionable.
Both offers two choices: sell directly to third parity or sell to company.
Direct buying (by the company for resale) services are called Instant Offer and RedfinNow
Claimed impZortant metric on 10K: online visitors</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>workshop: play text-based games with rl</title>
      <link>/posts/nlp_rl/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/nlp_rl/</guid>
      <description>Play interactive fiction games with reinforcement learning *A report written for school, thus the (annoying) verboseness
*Chose the topic thanks to the Wordplay workshop at NeurIPS 2020 (did not attend, just reading papers)
Contents
 Natural language tool definition Data and environment specifications Problem and algorithms Experiments and comparisons References  1 Natural language tool definition
The natural language tool this report evaluates is a reinforcement learning (RL) agent that plays a type of game called Interactive Fiction (IF).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lex podcast jot: meaning of life and human being 2-dimensional</title>
      <link>/posts/lex1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lex1/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VAE: reasoning process</title>
      <link>/posts/vae/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/vae/</guid>
      <description>No math, just bullet points! to stopped being constantly bothered by theories behind VAE.
Start with GMM: each z corresponds to a cluster.
Optimizing log probability of GMM: won’t work because you have to sample the unique z that correspond to an x. Otherwise the other sampled p(x|z) are virtually zero (so no gradients).
Distributed representation: an important catch: e.g. binary features result in 2^n, rather than n, clusters.
Thus, the chance of sampling a useful z is 1/(2^n).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
